Guide to the Paul Hibbert Clyde and Mary (Kestler) Clyde Papers, 1924-2001 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Inventory of the Paul Hibbert Clyde and Mary (Kestler) Clyde papers 1924-2001 and undated
Clyde, Paul Hibbert, 1896-
26 linear feet Extent: Approximately 16,985 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00237
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Some material is unprocessed and may need further processing before use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Biographical Note
Historian Paul Hibbert Clyde was born in Victoria, British Columbia, Canada in 1896. After receiving his Ph.D. from Stanford University in 1925, he taught history at Ohio State University (1925-1931), Stanford University (1928-1929), the University of Kentucky (1931-1937), and Duke University (1937-1961). A specialist in Far Eastern history, he wrote many articles and books on the subject, including a book-length work originally titled The Far East: A History of the Impact of the West on Eastern Asia, published in 1949 and revised in later years. He also served as a guest lecturer or consultant throughout his career. He also served with The Duke Endowment (1961-1970) as educational consultant.
Collection Overview
The Paul Hibbert Clyde and Mary (Kestler) Clyde Papers span the years 1924-2001 and chiefly consist of newspaper clippings, drafts of memoranda, and translations of foreign news reports, given to Paul Clyde by Hugh L. Keenleyside, who was first secretary of the Canadian Legation in Tokyo (1929-1936). Multiple additions of personal papers assembled by the Paul and Mary Clyde complete the collection.
The East Asian Clippings Files, the largest series in the collection, contain clippings assembled by the Clydes during the 1920s and 1930s from about thirty English language newspapers and news services in Canada, China, Great Britain, Japan, and the United States. Centering on Sino-Japanese relations, they concern contemporary political, social, economic, military, and international affairs in China, Japan, and Manchuria (Manchukuo), primarily from the perspective of Japan's role in these events. Files are arranged alphabetically by topic.
Materials in the Personal Papers Series, additions acquired from 1986 to 1999, consist chiefly of personal and professional correspondence, church records, manuscripts and a thesis, curriculum vitae of Paul Hibbert Clyde and his wife Mary Kestler Clyde, reprints of published articles, book revisions, other printed materials, additional news clippings, and photographs. The additions are partially processed or unprocessed. Much of the professional correspondence concerns Clyde’s work with the Duke Endowment, first as secretary to the Committee on Educational Institutions, and later as educational consultant to the Trustees of the Endowment. Correspondents include Mary and James H. Semans, and administrators at Davidson College, Furman University, and the University of Florida. There is also a folder of War Department Military Intelligence Division correspondence, 1942-1943. Also included is an album of photographs, clippings, invitations, and addresses compiled for the celebration of the Duke Endowment’s fortieth anniversary. Among the photographs is one of Mr. Thomas Perkins, a former chairman of the board of trustees of The Duke Endowment. Some of the personal correspondence relates to the death of Mrs. Clyde. The church records from the Independent Unitarian Church in Belleair Bluffs, Florida, include minutes and an address by Clyde on the major religions of China. A transcript of Dr. Clyde’s oral history tape regarding his tenure with Duke University, as well as his tenure as director of the Educational Division of the Duke Endowment is included. There is also a description by Mrs. Clyde relating to the launching and operating of the administrative areas of the Woman’s College (Duke University) in which she worked; information about her service as president of the Woman’s College Alumnae Association, 1966-1967; and the initiation that year of the idea of a Continuing Education Program at Duke.
Unprocessed additions are listed at the end of the collection's Detailed Description.
Subject Headings
Canada -- Foreign relations -- Japan; China -- History -- 1928-1937; China -- Religion; Clyde, Mary Kestler; Clyde, Paul Hibbert, 1896-; College teachers -- Correspondence; Duke Endowment -- History; Duke University -- History; Duke University. Woman's College -- History; Japan -- Foreign relations -- 20th century; Japan -- History -- 1912-1945; Keenleyside, Hugh Llewellyn, 1898-; Manchuria (China) -- History -- 1931-1945; Photograph albums; Semans, Mary Duke Biddle Trent; Semans, James H.; Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945; Unitarian churches -- Florida -- 20th century; United States -- Foreign relations
Contents of Collection
- East Asian Clippings Files, 1924-1938, (33 boxes)
  - Information File (Box 1)
  - America - Canada
    - America. Relations with Japan: 1931 (Box 1)
    - The Amur Incident: 1937 (Box 1)
    - Anti-British Propaganda: 1933 (Box 1)
    - Araki. General: 1933 (Box 1)
    - Arms. Embargo: 1933 (Box 1)
    - Attack on British Ambassador in China: 1937 (Box 1)
    - British Economic Mission: 1930 (Box 1)
    - British Trade Delegation: 1930 (Box 1)
    - British Trade Mission: 1930 (Box 1)
    - Budget and Taxation: 1936 (Box 1)
    - Budget, Taxation and Finance: 1936-1937, March (Box 1)
    - Budget, Taxation and Finance: 1937, Sept. -1938 (Box 1)
    - Canada. Japan: 1934-1937 (Box 1)
    - Canada. League [of Nations]: 1934 (Box 1)
    - Canada. Missions: 1934 (Box 1)
    - Canada. Naval: 1929 (Box 1)
    - Canada. Relations with China: 1932 (Box 1)
    - Canada. Relations with U.S.S.R.: 1931 (Box 1)
    - Canada. Trade with Japan: 1933 (Box 1)
  - China
    - China: 1929-1934, 1937, July (Box 2)
    - China: 1937, Aug.-1938 (Box 2)
    - China. Army: 1931 (Box 2)
    - China. Aviation: 1930 (Box 2)
    - China. Boycott: 1932 (Box 2)
    - China. Chinese Eastern Railway Affairs: l929-1935 (Box 2)
    - China. Civil War: 1929-1930, Feb. (Box 2)
  - China. Civil War: March, 1930 - China. Extraterritoriality
    - China, Civil War. 1930, March-June (Box 3)
    - China. Civil War. 1930, Aug.-1931 (Box 3)
    - China, Diplomatic: 1929, 1931 (Box 3)
    - China. Domestic Politics: 1929, 1932 (Box 3)
    - China. Drugs: 1930 (Box 3)
    - China. Economic: 1929-1933, 1935 (Box 3)
    - China. Education: 1930 (Box 3)
    - China. Extraterritoriality: 1929-1930, April (Box 3)
    - China. Extraterritoriality: 1930, May-1933 (Box 3)
  - China. Famine - China. Northern Government
    - China. Famine: 1929-1930 (Box 4)
    - China. Financial: 1929-1930 (Box 4)
    - China. Fianacial: 1931-1932 (Box 4)
    - China. Floods: 1938 (Box 4)
    - China. Foreign Relations: 1930-1931 (Box 4)
    - China, General: 1930-1933 (Box 4)
    - China. Hong Kong: 1930 (Box 4)
    - China, Hulutao Harbor: 1930 (Box 4)
    - China, Internal Politics: 1929 (Box 4)
    - China. League [of Nations]: 1932, 1934, 1937 (Box 4)
    - China. Manchuria: 1927, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
    - China. Military: 1931-1932 (Box 4)
    - China. Miscellaneous: 1931, 1934 (Box 4)
    - China, Missions: 1930 (Box 4)
    - China, Navigation: 1929-1930 (Box 4)
    - China. Northern Government: 1930 (Box 4)
  - China. Political
    - China, Political: 1929-1930, June (Box 5)
    - China. Political: 1930, July-Dec. (Box 5)
    - China. Political: 1931 (Box 5)
    - China. Political: 1932-1933, Sept. (Box 5)
  - China. Political - Diet
    - China. Political: 1933, Oct.-1934 (Box 6)
    - China. Relations with Japan: 1932 (Box 6)
    - China. Relations with U.S.S.R.: 1929-1933 (Box 6)
    - China: Shipping: 1929-1930 (Box 6)
    - China. Social: 1930 (Box 6)
    - China. Tariff: 1930 (Box 6)
    - China. Trade: 1930, 1932-1933 (Box 6)
    - China. U.S.A.: 1933-1934 (Box 6)
    - China. War With: 1933 (Box 6)
    - China. Weihaiwei: 1930 (Box 6)
    - Chinese Students: 1931 (Box 6)
    - Diet: 1933, 1935-1936 (Box 6)
    - Diet: 1937, Jan. (Box 6)
    - Diet: 1937, Feb. (Box 6)
  - Diet, 1937-1938
    - Diet: 1937, March (Box 7)
    - Diet: 1937, April (Box 7)
    - Diet: 1937, May-June (Box 7)
    - Diet: 1937, Aug.-Dec. (Box 7)
    - Diet: 1938, Jan.-Feb. (Box 7)
    - Diet: 1938, March (Box 7)
  - Diet - Germano-Japanese Agreement
    - Diet: 1938, April (Box 8)
    - Diet: 1938, May-Oct. (Box 8)
    - Economic Conference: 1933 (Box 8)
    - Economic Development of Manchuria and North China: 1937 (Box 8)
    - Europe: 1935, 1938 (Box 8)
    - Fall of the Hyashi Government: 1937 (Box 8)
    - Fishing: 1936-1937 (Box 8)
    - Foreign Exchange Fund: 1938 (Box 8)
    - Freda Utley, Agriculture, Labor, etc.: 1937-1938 (Box 8)
    - Germano-Japanese Agreement: 1936-1937 (Box 8)
  - Germany - International
    - Germany: 1937-1938 (Box 9)
    - Gold, Bonds, Thrift Campaign: 1938 (Box 9)
    - Gold, Currency, Bonds: 1937 (Box 9)
    - Great Britain. China: 1929-1938 (Box 9)
    - Great Britain. Foreign Policy: 1933-1934 (Box 9)
    - Great Britain. Japan: 1931-1938 (Box 9)
    - Great Britain. Naval Conference: 1929 (Box 9)
    - Great Britain. Political: 1935 (Box 9)
    - Great Britain. Trade: 1930 (Box 9)
    - Imperial Headquarters and Cabinet Reorganization: 1937 (Box 9)
    - India: 1933, 1935 (Box 9)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations: 1933 (Box 9)
    - International: 1931 (Box 9)
  - Iron Imports - Japan. Army
    - Iron Imports and Economic Plane: 1937 (Box 10)
    - Italo-Japan ese Agreement: 1936 (Box 10)
    - Japan: 1931-1937 (Box 10)
    - Japan: 1938 (Box 10)
    - Japan. Agriculture: 1930-1935 (Box 10)
    - Japan. Aluminum: 1933 (Box 10)
    - Japan. Arlmarlen: 1933-1935 (Box 10)
    - Japan. Army: 1929-1935 (Box 10)
  - Japan. Army and Navy - Japan. Colonial Policy: October, 1936
    - Japan. Army and Navy: 1936-1937 (Box 11)
    - Japan. Australia: 1934-1935 (Box 11)
    - Japan. Automobile Development: 1929 (Box 11)
    - Japan. Biographical: 1931, 1933 (Box 11)
    - Japan. Birth Control: 1929-1930, 1938 (Box 11)
    - Japan. Brazil: 1934 (Box 11)
    - Japan. Budget: 1929 (Box 11)
    - Japan. Colonial Policy: 1930, 1936, Feb.-May (Box 11)
    - Japan. Colonial Policy: 1936, June-Sept. (Box 11)
    - Japan. Colonial Policy: 1936, Oct. (Box 11)
  - Japan. Colonial Policy - Japan. Economic
    - Japan. Colonial Policy: 1936, Nov.-1937, Sept. (Box 12)
    - Japan. Colonial Policy: 1937, Oct.-1938 (Box 12)
    - Japan. Communism: 1929, 1933-1934 (Box 12)
    - Japan. Cotton: 1934 (Box 12)
    - Japan. Diplomatic: 1931-1934 (Box 12)
    - Japan. Disarmament: 1931-1934 (Box 12)
    - Japan. Dutch East Indies: 1934 (Box 12)
    - Japan. Economic: 1929-1930 (Box 12)
    - Japan. Economic: 1931-1932 (Box 12)
  - Japan. Economic
    - Japan. Economic: 1933-1934 (Box 13)
    - Japan. Economic: 1935, Jan.-Oct. (Box 13)
    - Japan. Economic: 1935, Nov.-Dec. (Box 13)
    - Japan. Economic: 1936 (Box 13)
    - Japan. Economic: 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - Japan. Factory Reform - Japan. Financial
    - Japan. Factory Reform: 1929 (Box 14)
    - Japan. Fascism: 1933 (Box 14)
    - Japan. Finances: 1937 (Box 14)
    - Japan. Financial: 1924-1930 (Box 14)
    - Japan. Financial: 1931 (Box 14)
    - Japan. Financial: 1932 (Box 14)
  - Japan. Financial - Japan. Food
    - Japan. Financial: 1933-1935 (Box 15)
    - Japan. Financial and Economic: 1936 (Box 15)
    - Japan. Financial and Economic: 1937, Jan.-April (Box 15)
    - Japan. Financial and Economic: 1937, May-July (Box 15)
    - Japan. Fisheries: 1931, 1934 - 1935 (Box 15)
    - Japan. Food: 1929-1930 (Box 15)
  - Japan. Foreign Policy - Japan. League of Nations
    - Japan. Foreign Policy: 1929-1935 (Box 16)
    - Japan. Foreign Relations: 1929-1934 (Box 16)
    - Japan. Foreign Trade: 1935 (Box 16)
    - Japan. France: 1932-1935 (Box 16)
    - Japan. General: 1930, 1932 (Box 16)
    - Japan. Gold Embargo: 1924 (Box 16)
    - Japan. Immigration: 1930 (Box 16)
    - Japan. India: 1933-1934 (Box 16)
    - Japan. Industrial: 1929-1930 (Box 16)
    - Japan. Labor: 1929-1935 (Box 16)
    - Japan. League of Nations: 1930-1937 (Box 16)
  - Japan. Literature - Japan. Miscellaneous
    - Japan. Literature: 1936 (Box 17)
    - Japan. Manchuria: 1931-1932 (Box 17)
    - Japan. Mandated Islands: 1934-1935 (Box 17)
    - Japan. Military: 1931-1933 (Box 17)
    - Japan. Miscellaneous: 1933-1936 (Box 17)
    - Japan. Miscellaneous: 1937, Jan.-June (Box 17)
    - Japan. Miscellaneous: 1937, July-Dec. (Box 17)
    - Japan. Miscellaneous: 1938, Jan.-May (Box 17)
    - Japan. Miscellaneous: 1938, June-Aug. (Box 17)
  - Japan. Missions - Japan. Naval
    - Japan. Missions: 1935 (Box 18)
    - Japan. Narcotics: 1933 (Box 18)
    - Japan. Naval: 1929 (Box 18)
    - Japan. Naval: 1930, Jan.-July (Box 18)
    - Japan. Naval: 1930, Aug.-Dec. (Box 18)
    - Japan. Naval: 1931-1933 (Box 18)
    - Japan. Naval: 1934-1935, 1938 (Box 18)
  - Japan. Overseas - Japan. Political
    - Japan. Overseas Affairs Department: 1929 (Box 19)
    - Japan. Political: 1929 (Box 19)
    - Japan. Political: 1930 (Box 19)
    - Japan. Political: 1931, Jan.-May (Box 19)
    - Japan. Political: 1931, June-Dec. (Box 19)
    - Japan. Political: 1932, Jan.-June (Box 19)
    - Japan. Political: 1932, July-Dec. (Box 19)
  - Japan. Political
    - Japan. Political: 1933, Jan.-May (Box 20)
    - Japan. Political: 1933, June-Dec. (Box 20)
    - Japan. Political: 1934 (Box 20)
    - Japan. Political: 1935 (Box 20)
  - Japan. Political
    - Japan. Political: 1937, June-Aug. (Box 21)
    - Japan. Political: 1937, Sept.-Nov. (Box 21)
    - Japan. Political: 1937, Dec. (Box 21)
    - Japan. Political: 1938, Jan.-March (Box 21)
    - Japan. Political: 1938, April-Sept. (Box 21)
  - Japan. Political Situation - Japan. Relations with China
    - Japan. Political Situation: 1937 (Box 22)
    - Japan. Population: 1929-1934 (Box 22)
    - Japan. Press: 1931-1938 (Box 22)
    - Japan. Radical Party: 1929-1934 (Box 22)
    - Japan. Railways: 1930-1933 (Box 22)
    - Japan. Relations with China: 1929-1930 (Box 22)
    - Japan. Relations with China: 1931, Jan.-Oct. (Box 22)
    - Japan. Relations with China: 1931, Nov.-Dec. (Box 22)
  - Japan. Relations with China - Japan. Relations with U.S.S.R.
    - Japan. Relations with China: 1932-1934 (Box 23)
    - Japan. Relations with China: 1935-1938 (Box 23)
    - Japan. Relations with Great Britain: 1929-1935 (Box 23)
    - Japan. Relations with U.S.S.R,: 1930-1931 (Box 23)
    - Japan. Relations with U.S.S,R,: 1932 (Box 23)
  - Japan. Relations with U.S.S.R. - Japan. Shipping
    - Japan. Relations with U.S.S.R.: 1933 (Box 24)
    - Japan. Relations with U.S.S.R.: 1934-1935 (Box 24)
    - Japan. Relations with U.S.A.: 1930-1932 (Box 24)
    - Japan. Relations with U.S.A.: 1933-1938 (Box 24)
    - Japan. Shipping: 1929-1936 (Box 24)
  - Japan. Shipping - Leprosy
    - Japan. Shipping: 1937 (Box 25)
    - Japan. Sociological: 1929-1933 (Box 25)
    - Japan. Speeches: 1930 (Box 25)
    - Japan. Spies: 1936 (Box 25)
    - Japan. Tariff: 1929-1930 (Box 25)
    - Japan. Trade: 1929-1936 (Box 25)
    - Japan. Wheat: 1934 (Box 25)
    - Japanese-British Cooperation: 1937 (Box 25)
    - Konoe Cabinet and Special Diet Session: 1937 (Box 25)
    - League of Nations: 1930-1931 (Box 25)
    - League of Nations: 1932 (Box 25)
    - League of Nations, U.S.A.: 1931-1932 (Box 25)
    - Leprosy: 1936 (Box 25)
  - Manchuria, 1931
    - Manchuria: 1931, Sept. (Box 26)
    - Manchuria: 1931, Oct. 1-13 (Box 26)
    - Manchuria: 1931, Oct. 14-31 (Box 26)
    - Manchuria: 1931, Nov. (Box 26)
    - Manchuria: 1931, Nov. (Box 26)
  - Manchuria, 1932-1935
    - Manchuria: 1932, Jan.-June (Box 27)
    - Manchuria: 1932, July-Dec. (Box 27)
    - Manchuria 1933, Jan.-April (Box 27)
    - Manchuria: 1933, May-Dec. (Box 27)
    - Manchuria: 1934, Jan.-Sept. (Box 27)
    - Manchuria: 1934, Oct.-Dec. (Box 27)
    - Manchuria: 1935-1936 (Box 27)
  - Manchuria. Bandits - Manchuria. Customs
    - Manchuria. Bandits: 1932 (Box 28)
    - Manchuria, Customs: 1932 (Box 28)
    - Manchuria, Customs: 1937 (Box 28)
    - Manchuria, Customs: 1938, Jan.-Feb. (Box 28)
    - Manchuria. Customs: 1938, March-July (Box 28)
  - Manchuria. Customs - Manchuria. League of Nations
    - Manchuria. Customs: 1938, Aug.-Sept. (Box 29)
    - Manchuria, Kinney report [memorandum]: 1933 (Box 29)
    - Manchuria. League Commission: 1932 (Box 29)
    - Manchuria. League of Nations: 1932-1933 (Box 29)
    - Manchuria. League of Nations: 1937, Aug.-Sept. (Box 29)
    - Manchuria. League of Nations: 1937, Oct. (Box 29)
    - Manchuria. League of Nations: 1937, Nov.-Dec. (Box 29)
    - Manchuria. League of Nations: 1938, Jan.-Feb. (Box 29)
  - Manchuria. League of Nations: March, 1938 - Naval Conference
    - Manchuria. League of Nations: 1938, March-April (Box 30)
    - Manchuria. League [of Nations] Withdrawal: 1933 (Box 30)
    - Manchuria, Lytton Report: 1932-1933 (Box 30)
    - Manchuria. Monarchy: 1934 (Box 30)
    - Manchuria. Passports and Naturalization: 1932-1933 (Box 30)
    - Manchuria. Political: 1932-1933 (Box 30)
    - Manchuria. Postal Service: 1932 (Box 30)
    - Manchuria. Railways: 1931, 1933 (Box 30)
    - Manchuria. Recognition: 1932-1935 (Box 30)
    - Naval Conference: 1929-1930 (Box 30)
  - New Cabinet - Singapore
    - New Cabinet: 1938 (Box 31)
    - North China: 1933 (Box 31)
    - North China, Incidents (Peiping): 1937-1938 (Box 31)
    - Pacific: 1930, 1936 (Box 31)
    - Price Commission: 1937-1938 (Box 31)
    - Radio: 1930 (Box 31)
    - Shanghai: 1930, 1932 (Box 31)
    - Shanghai: 1937-1938 (Box 31)
    - Singapore: 1930 (Box 31)
  - Sino-Japanese Relations
    - Sino-Japanese Relations: 1936 (Box 32)
    - Sino-Japanese Relations: 1937, Jan. (Box 32)
    - Sino-Japanese Relations: 1937, Feb. (Box 32)
    - Sino-Japanese Relations: 1937, March (Box 32)
    - Sino-Japanese Relations: 1937, April-May (Box 32)
  - Sino-Japanese Relations - U.S.A. Japan
    - Sino-Japanese Relations: 1937, June (Box 33)
    - Sino-Japanese Relations: 1937, July-Aug. (Box 33)
    - South Manchuria Railway: 1934, 1936 (Box 33)
    - Soviet. Manchuria: 1932 (Box 33)
    - Tokyo: 1933 (Box 33)
    - U.S.S.R.: 1932 (Box 33)
    - U.S.S.R. Great Britain: 1933 (Box 33)
    - U.S.S.R. Relations with China: 1931 (Box 33)
    - U.S.S.R. Relations with Japan: 1931-1938 (Box 33)
    - U.S.A. Far East:1932, 1937-1938 (Box 33)
    - U.S.A. Foreign Policy:1934 (Box 33)
    - U.S.A. and Japan: 1930, 1937-1938 (Box 33)
- Personal Papers Series, 1929-2001 and undated, (15 boxes)
  - 1986 Addition, 1935-1998, (12 boxes)
    Addition is partially processed; papers have not been arranged beyond original order and may need further processing before materials can be accessed for research.
    - Correspondence, 1963-1976 (Box 1, Acc. 1986)
    - Addresses (Box 2, Acc. 1986)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1983 (Box 2, Acc. 1986)
    - Legal papers (Box 2, Acc. 1986)
    - Harold Eugene Davis: An Autobiography (Box 2, Acc. 1986)
    - American Historical Association, 1947-1961 (Box 3, Acc. 1986)
    - American University; Biarritz, France, 1945 (Box 3, Acc. 1986)
    - Book reviews (Box 4, Acc. 1986)
    - American Assembly, 1961 (Box 4, Acc. 1986)
    - Canada-U.S. treaty relations (Box 4, Acc. 1986)
    - University documents (Box 4, Acc. 1986)
    - Duke University (Box 4, Acc. 1986)
    - Furman University (Box 4, Acc. 1986)
    - Davidson College (Box 4, Acc. 1986)
    - Correspondence - Canadian Institute of International Affairs (Box 4, Acc. 1986)
    - Speeches and addresses (Box 4, Acc. 1986)
    - Correspondence (Box 5, Acc. 1986)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations (Box 5, Acc. 1986)
    - The Citadel (Box 5, Acc. 1986)
    - Iowa State University (Box 5, Acc. 1986)
    - Johns Hopkins Press (Box 5, Acc. 1986)
    - Individuals (Box 5, Acc. 1986)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Acc. 1986)
    - Duke University (Box 6, Acc. 1986)
    - Photos from inaguration of President Arthur Hollis Edens, 1949 (Box 6, Acc. 1986)
    - Faculty Club, 1942-1945 (Box 6, Acc. 1986)
    - International studies program, 1960 (Box 6, Acc. 1986)
    - Research Council (Box 6, Acc. 1986)
    - Undergraduate Faculty Council (Box 6, Acc. 1986)
    - University Council (Box 6, Acc. 1986)
    - University faculty, 1960 (Box 6, Acc. 1986)
    - Individual correspondence (Box 6, Acc. 1986)
    - General correspondence (Box 7, Acc. 1986)
    - Paul Hibbert Clyde personal library holdings and correspondence, 1961 (Box 7, Acc. 1986)
    - Papers and presentations (Box 7, Acc. 1986)
    - Copyright law correspondence, 1965 (Box 7, Acc. 1986)
    - Salzburg Seminar in American Studies (Box 8, Acc. 1986)
    - School of Advanced International Studies (Box 8, Acc. 1986)
    - Correspondence (Box 8, Acc. 1986)
    - South Carolina Foundation of Independent Colleges (Box 9, Acc. 1986)
    - University of South Florida (Box 9, Acc. 1986)
    - Southwestern at Memphis (Box 9, Acc. 1986)
    - Stanford Education Society, Inc. (Box 9, Acc. 1986)
    - Standard Oil (Box 9, Acc. 1986)
    - Stanford University (Box 9, Acc. 1986)
    - War Department Military Intelligence Division correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 9, Acc. 1986)
    - Paul Hibbert Clyde calendars, 1962-1968 (Box 9, Acc. 1986)
    - University files (Box 10, Acc. 1986)
    - Speeches and remarks (Box 10, Acc. 1986)
    - Correspondence (Box 10, Acc. 1986)
    - Academic papers (Box 10, Acc. 1986)
    - Correspondence (Box 11, Acc. 1986)
    - Personal (Box 11, Acc. 1986)
    - Academic (Box 11, Acc. 1986)
    - University files (Box 11, Acc. 1986)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 11, Acc. 1986)
    - The Duke Endowment (Box 12, Acc. 1986)
    - Pamphlets (Box 12, Acc. 1986)
    - Notecards (Box 12, Acc. 1986)
    - Correspondence (Box 12, Acc. 1986)
    - Paul Hibbert Clyde memoir for Duke University archives (Box 12, Acc. 1986)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 12, Acc. 1986)
    - Includes a photograph album (Box 13, Acc. 1986)
- Unprocessed additions, (5 boxes and 5 folders)
  Unprocessed additions include materials that have arrived post-processing, and have not yet been integrated into the rest of the collection. These items are open for research but have limited description available.
  - 1987 Feb. 24 Addition, 1984-1987, (2 folders) (Box 12, Acc. 1986)
    Folders contain correspondence from 1984-1987, Mary Kestler's master's thesis, and a draft for an article on Howell's personal and literary association with Samuel Clemens (Mark Twain).
  - 1987 Oct. 22 Addition, 1986-1987, (1 folder) (Box 1, Add. 1981-1989)
    Contains correspondence for the years 1986-1987 and clippings.
  - 1988 July 26 Addition, 1987-1988, (1 folder) (Box 1, Add. 1981-1989)
    Contains correspondence for the years 1987-1988 and papers concerning a tribute to Dr. Mattie Russell.
  - 1989 June 17 Addition, 1988-1989, (1 folder) (Box 1, Add. 1981-1989)
    Contains correspondence for the years 1988-1989 and photographic material.
  - Other Additions, 1929-1936, (1 box)
    Accessions 90-013, 91-033, 91-113, 91-151, 92-038, 92-089, and 93-183. Contains personal files and correspondence, as well as newspaper clippings from Japan and the United States in English which relate to Manchukuo, Mongolia and Siam Revolt.
    - Unprocessed materials (Box 1, Acc. 90/093)
    - Unprocessed materials (Box 1, Acc. 97/024)